Friedlander, Walter A.; Papers ger003
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence files, 1918-1984; 2; 3,383 folders
  - Correspondence, chronological files, 1914-1984; 2.8; 59 folders, approx. 972 items of correspondence
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1914-1933 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1934 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1935 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1936 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1937 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1938 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1939 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1940 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1942 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1943 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1944 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1945 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1946 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1947 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1948 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1949 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1950 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1951 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1952 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1953 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1954 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1955 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1956 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1957 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1958 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1959 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 26)
    - Emeritation, 1959 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 27)
      Souvenir notebook
    - Retirement congratulations - University of California, Berkeley, faculty and staff, 1959 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 28)
    - Retirement congratulations (A-F), 1959 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 29)
    - Retirement congratulations (G-L), 1959 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 30)
    - Retirement congratulations (M-Z), 1959 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 31)
    - Retirement dinner - Regrets, 1959 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1960 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1961 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 34)
    - 75th Birthday congratulations, 1961 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1962 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1963 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1964 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1965 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 39)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1966 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 40)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1967 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 41)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1968 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1969 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 43)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1970 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1971 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 45)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1972 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 46)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1973 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 47)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1974 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 48)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1975 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 49)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1976 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 50)
    - 85th Birthday congratulations, 1976 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 51)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1977 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 52)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1978 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 53)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1979 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 54)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1981 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 55)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1982 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 56)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1983 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 57)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified, 1984 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 58)
    - 93rd Birthday congratulations, 1984 (Box 31 (2-Correspondence files), Folder 59)
- Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. Friedländer, 1931-1984; 3; 341 folders
  This series contains typescripts and manuscripts of full-length works, including textbooks; typescripts and manuscripts of journal publications in German and in English; and typescripts and manuscripts of books reviewed by Friedländer. Versions of several of Friedländer's full-length works are present, including: Einführung in die soziale Wohlfahrt, Helene Simon, Individualism & Social Welfare, International Social Welfare, and Introduction to Social Welfare. Versions of many of Friedländer's German-language journal articles (184 folders), 1931-1984, include many articles dating from the 1930s dealing with topics and problems associated with Friedländer's experiences as Head of the Jugendamt in the Prenzlauer-Berg section of Berlin until 1933. Also present in this section are typescripts and manuscripts of journal articles written in English (49 folders), 1932-1979. The final section (62 folders) contains typescripts and manuscripts of book reviews by W.F. in both German and English.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Miscellaneous notes and book manuscripts, 3.1
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1940s (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1950s (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1960s (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1970s (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 4)
    - American Oxford Encyclopedia -- Articles A-D, ca. 1961 (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 5)
    - American Oxford Encyclopedia -- Articles H-M, ca. 1961 (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 6)
    - American Oxford Encyclopedia -- Articles N-P, ca. 1961 (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 7)
    - American Oxford Encyclopedia -- Articles Q-W, ca. 1961 (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 8)
    - American Oxford Encyclopedia -- page proofs, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 9)
    - Einführung in die soziale Wohlfahrt, pp. i-ix, 1-99, 1968 (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 10)
    - Einführung in die soziale Wohlfahrt, pp. 100-233, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 11)
    - Einführung in die soziale Wohlfahrt, pp. 234-350, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 12)
    - Einführung in die soziale Wohlfahrt, pp. 351-485, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 13)
    - Einführung in die soziale Wohlfahrt, pp. 486-590, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 14)
    - Einführung in die soziale Wohlfahrt, pp. 591-719, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 15)
    - Einführung in die soziale Wohlfahrt, pp. 720-851, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 16)
    - Helene Simon -- Notes pertaining to works by and about H. Simon, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 17)
    - Helene Simon -- Sections in German, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 18-21)
    - Helene Simon. Ein Leben für soziale Gerechtigkeit, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 22)
    - Helene Simon. Ein Leben für soziale Gerechtigkeit -- page proofs, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 23)
    - Helene Simon -- Drafts of English version, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 24)
    - Helene Simon, German Pioneer. Chapters in English, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 25)
    - Helene Simon. Pioneer of Child Welfare and Social Legislation, (1963); 97p. (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 26)
    - Helene Simon. German Pioneer in Child Welfare and Social Legislation, Undated; 138p., 2 folders (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 27-28)
    - Helene Simon: Pioneer in Child Welfare and Social Legislation, Undated; 135p. (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 29)
    - Hugo Haase. Preface, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 30)
    - Hugo Haase. Notes, Undated (Box 32 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 31)
    - Individualism & Social Welfare, Undated (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 32)
    - International Social Welfare -- notes, Undated (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 33)
    - International Aspects of Social Welfare, ca. 1973 (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 34)
    - International Aspects of Social Welfare, Undated (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 35)
    - Introduction to Social Welfare -- Table of Contents, page proofs, Undated (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 36)
    - Introduction to Social Welfare -- Chapter 13, (1955) (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 37)
    - Introduction to Social Welfare -- Tables of contents, chapters 21, 22, Undated (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 38)
    - Introduction to Social Welfare -- bibliographies, Undated (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 39)
    - Introduction to Social Welfare -- photographs, charts, tables, Undated (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 40)
    - Introduction to Social Welfare -- galley proofs, Undated (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 41)
    - Introduction to Social Welfare -- Appendix, galley proofs, Undated (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 42)
    - Introduction to Social Welfare -- Revisions, 1959-1960 (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 43)
    - Introduction to Social Welfare -- Third edition, revisions, Undated (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 44)
    - Introduction to Social Welfare -- Third edition, page proofs, Undated (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 45)
    - Introduction to Social Welfare -- Revisions, 1977-1979 (Box 33 (3-Manuscripts/typescripts by Walter A. ), Folder 46)
  - Manuscripts of journal articles, 3.2
    - German articles, Undated; 3.2.1
      - "Adele Schreiber zu ihrem 60. Geburtstag", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 47)
      - "Amerikanische Jugendhilfe 1930-1940", (1941) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 48)
      - "Amerikanische Jugendwohlfahrts-Konferenz", (1960) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 49)
      - "Das amerikanische Krankenhaus-Versicherungsgesetz von 1960", (1965) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 50)
      - "Die amerikanische Nationale Konferenz für Wohlfahrtspflege" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 51)
      - "Der amerikanische 'Social Security Act' in der Praxis" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 52)
      - "Die amerikanische Wohlfahrtskonferenz", (1955) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 53)
      - "Amerikanische Wohlfahrtskonferenz in Los Angeles", (1964) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 54)
      - "Die amerikanische Wohlfahrtskonferenz in Seattle", (1938) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 55)
      - "Amerikanische Wohlfahrtskonferenz und Landesverteidigung", (1942) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 56)
      - "Amerikas Sorgen bei der Finanzierung der freien Wohlfahrts- und Jugendwohlfahrtspflege", (ca. 1952) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 57)
      - "Arbeitslosigkeit und Kinderarbeit", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 58)
      - "Das Arbeitsproblem der deutschen Emigranten", (1933) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 59)
      - "Armut in Amerika", (1965) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 60)
      - "Auffangsgrenzen für Fürsorgeleistung in USA", (1953) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 61)
      - "Aufgaben und Zusammenarbeit der privaten und staatlichen Jugendhilfe in den USA", (1952) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 62)
      - "Der Ausbau der amerikanischen Wohlfahrtspflege", (1939) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 63)
      - "Ausbau der öffentlichen Familienfürsorge in Amerika", (1957) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 64)
      - "Der Ausbau der Sozialversicherung in den Vereinigten Staaten" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 65)
      - "Bedauerliche Vorkommnisse in Deutschland", (1979) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 66)
      - "Bekämpfung der Arbeitslosigkeit in den Vereinigten Staaten", (1937) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 67)
      - "Beobachtungen auf der Internationale Konferenz für soziale Arbeit" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 68)
      - "Bericht über die 16. Internationale Konferenz für soziale Arbeit", (1972) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 69)
      - "Das Berufsbildungswesen in den Vereinigten Staaten", (1954) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 70)
      - "Die beste Verteidigung der Freiheit", (1941) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 71)
      - "Betr. Gutachten über Abgabe von Arzneien in den Betratungsstellen", (1931) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 72)
      - "Bevölkerungspolitik im Dritten Reich", (1933) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 73)
      - "Die Bewegung der revolutionären Sozialisten Deutschlands", (ca. 1933) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 74)
      - "Deutsche Emigranten in Paris", (1933) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 75)
      - "Die deutsche Schipperkrankheit", (ca. 1938) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 76)
      - "Die deutsche Verfassung", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 77)
      - "Deutsche Zentrale für freie Jugendwohlfahrt", (1931) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 78)
      - "Deutsches Archiv für Jugendwohlfahrt. Die Altersstufen der Minderjährigen in der Reichsgesetzgebung", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 79)
      - "Dr. Otto Reinemann, Philadelphia: 70 Jahre alt" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 80)
      - "Ein amerikanisches Jugendgerichtgesetz", (1938) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 81)
      - "Ein dörfliches Entwicklungsprogramm in Griechenland" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 82)
      - "Ein Feldzug gegen das Verbrechertum in USA", (1937) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 83)
      - "Ein Merkblatt für die Fürsorgeerziehung", (1931) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 84)
      - "Ein Notprogramm der Fürsorgeerziehung", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 85)
      - "Ein Notprogramm der Jugendwohlfahrtspflege", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 86)
      - "Ein Notwerk der deutschen Jugend", (ca. 1933) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 87)
      - "Eine Krankenvericherung für die alternde Bevölkerung in den Vereinigten Staaten", (1965) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 88)
      - "Eine neue Adoptionsvermittlungsstelle?", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 89)
      - "Einige Anmerkungen zur Frage 'Überfluss und Armut in den Vereinigten Staaten'", (1964) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 90)
      - "Einige Bemerkungen zum Fluchtlingsproblem", (1984) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 91)
      - "Einige Erinnerungen an die Entwicklung der Arbeiterwohlfahrt und der deutschen Sozialarbeit nach 1918", (1968) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 92)
      - "Einige Gedanken über den Einfluss der deutschen Emigration während der Hitler-Zeit auf die amerikanische Sozialforschung", (1979) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 93)
      - "Einige neue Gesichtspunkte in der internationalen Sozialhilfe" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 94)
      - "Einundzwanzigster Jahresbericht der Deutschen Landeskommission für Kinderschutz und Jugendfürsorge in Mähren 1931", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 95)
      - "Emigranten in Paris", (1933) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 96)
      - "Entwicklung der Ausbildung für die soziale Arbeit in Israel" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 97)
      - "Die Entwicklung der sozialen Sicherung in U.S.A", (1960) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 98)
      - "Die Entwicklung der Sozialpädagogik als akademisches Lehr- und Forshungsfach in internationaler Sicht", (ca. 1974) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 99)
      - "Erfahrtungen in der deutschen Fürsorge für jugendliche Arbeitslose", (1933) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 100)
      - "Erfahrungen mit Ambulatorien in Amerika" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 101)
      - "Erfolg der Notprogramme in Thüringen", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 102)
      - "Erinnerung an Dr. Käthe Mende", (1964) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 103)
      - "Erinnerungen an die Entwicklung der sozialpädagoschen Bewegung in Deutschland in der Weimarer Republik und ihre Auswirkungen" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 104)
      - "Erinnerungen an die Entwicklung der sozialpädagogischen Konzeption in der Jugendhilfe in der Weimarer Periode vor 1933" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 105)
      - "Erziehungsberatung in U.S.A.", ca. 1960 (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 106)
      - "Fachkonferenz für die Ausgestaltung des freiwilligen Arbeitsdienstes für Frauen", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 107)
      - "Familienfürsorge und Krankenpflege in USA", (1958) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 108)
      - "Die Folgen des Krieges für die Kinder", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 109)
      - "Freiwillige Krankenversicherungen unter der Kaiser Stiftung in Kalifornien", (1953) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 110)
      - "Fürsorgeerziehung und Amtsvormundschaft", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 111)
      - "Fürsorgemaßnahmen zu Gunsten jugendlicher Arbeitslose. (Ergebnisse, Beurteilung und Vorschläge)", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 112)
      - "Fürsorgerische Mitwirkung bei der Behandlung chronisch Geisteskranker" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 113)
      - "Funktion der Sozialarbeit in der heutigen Gesellschaft" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 114)
      - "Gefahren für das demokratische Deutschland" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 115)
      - "Gefahrend des Ueberflusses" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 116)
      - "Gemeingefährliche Trinker", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 117)
      - "Gemeinsame Arbeit und Erlebnisse. Zu Lotte Lemkes 60. Geburtstag", (1962) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 118)
      - "Gemeinschaftplanung und Gemeinschaftsentwicklung in USA", (1962) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 119)
      - "Gesetzliche Regelung der sozialen Gerichtshilfe", (1933) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 120)
      - "Grundfragen der amerikanischen Sozialarbeit" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 121)
      - "Die Haltung amerikanischer Kinder zum Kriege", (1942) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 122)
      - "Hans Meier -- Sein Leben und Werk", (1964) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 123)
      - "Hauspflege in den Vereinigten Staaten", (1960) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 124)
      - "Die heutige Wohlfahrtspflegerische Mission der Schweiz", (1933) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 125)
      - "Hitler und die Reichswehr", (1942) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 126)
      - "Im Gegensatz zum früheren deutschen Recht..", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 127)
      - "In memoriam Hans Meier" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 128)
      - "In Memoriam René Sand (1877-1953)" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 129)
      - "Das internationale Fluchtlingsproblem und die Rolle der nationale Wohlfahrtsverbande", (1984) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 130)
      - "Internationale Sozialkonferenz in Toronto" (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 131)
      - "Internationale Vereinigung für Kinderhilfe in Genf", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 132)
      - "Internationaler Kinderschutzkongress in Deutschland", (1939) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 133)
      - "Jahresbericht für das Jahr 1931 des Jugend- und Fürsorgeamtes der Stadt Halle", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 134)
      - "'Den Juden geschieht nichts'", (1933) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 135)
      - "Jugend im Konflikt mit der Gesellschaft", (1965) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 136)
      - "Jugendamt und Fürsorgeerziehung", (1931) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 137)
      - "Jugendamt und Vormundschaftsgericht", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 138)
      - "Jugendhilfe auf der Landeskonferenz in New Orleans", (1942) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 139)
      - "Jugendhilfskonferenz im Weissen Haus", (1940) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 140)
      - "Jugendliche Banden in Amerika: ihre soziologische Rolle und Massnahmen der Fürsorge", (1962) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 141)
      - "Jugendliche Kriminalität im Kriege. Erfahrungen in England und in den Vereinigten Staaten", (1942) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 142)
      - "Das Jugendnotwerk in der Praxis", (1933) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 143)
      - "Der Kampf gegen die Armut in USA", (1967) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 144)
      - "Der Kampf um die Erhaltung der Jugendwohlfahrtspflege", (1932) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 145)
      - "Kann der Hauswirt das Flaggen verbieten?", (1933) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 146)
      - "Kinder in einer Demokratie. Die Jugendhilfe-Konferenz im Weissen Haus, Washington, D.C." (1940) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 147)
      - "Kleinkindererholung und Familienfürsorge", (1931) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 148)
      - "Kollegialbeschlüsse der Jugendämter", (1931) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 149)
      - "Die Krankenversicherung für die alternde Bevölkerung in Amerika", (1965) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 150)
      - "Landes-Wohlfahrtskongress in New Orleans", (1942) (Box 33 (3.2.1-German articles), Folder 151)